KOSTIANTYN OVSIANNIKOV

My academic interests include corporate governance, labor economics and determinants of innovation from the institutional and resourse-based perspectives. In my dissertation, I explored how the pursuit of shareholder-value by management has affected labor policies at large Japanese enterprises.

My current research project funded by the JSPS Grant-in-Aid for Young Scientists (B) focuses on the market perception of corporate innovations in Japan.



EDUCATION

2018 2015

Ph.D., Japanese Studies & Political Economy

University of Tsukuba

Tsukuba. Ibaraki. JP

- - · Dissertation: Japan's Corporate Governance Reforms, Effects on Corporate Dynamics and Labor-Related Repercussions
 - · Grant: Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology of Japan (MEXT)

2015 2014

M.A., International Area Studies

University of Tsukuba

Tsukuba, Ibaraki, JP

- Thesis: Stakeholder Model of Corporate Governance in Japan: Institutional Context of the 2002 Commercial Code Reform
- · Grant: Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology of Japan (MEXT)

2014 2011

M.A., Global Political Economy

University of Kassel

• Kassel, Hessen, GER

- Thesis: The Impact of the 'Companyist Compromise' on Japan's Financialization during 1980-90s
- · Grant: German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD) / Open Society Foundations (OSF)

2011 2007

B.A., Political Science

National University of Kyiv-Mohyla Academy

♀ Kyiv, UKR

- Thesis: Formation of the Japanese Geopolitical Strategy through Cultural-Historical Factors
- · Grant: Ukrainian Ministry of Education



TEACHING EXPERIENCE

· "English: Speaking & Listening"

Current 2021

Part-Time Lecturer

College of Humanities and Sciences

Nihon University



OVERVIEW

Date of birth: 15 August 1990 Nationality: Ukraine Gender: Male

CONTACT

Ø kovsiannikov.com

■ k.ovsiannikov@gmail.com

y kovsiann

? ko-suta

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Japanese (business level)

Last updated on 2021-06-27

2020 | 2019 Current | 2021 Current | 2018

Part-Time Lecturer

Economics Department

- Opokkyo University
- · "Introduction to Economics" (2nd-year students)
- · "Microeconomics" (3rd-year students)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Postdoc

School of Economics & Management

♥ Kochi University of Technology

- Conducting a research project on the impact of telework on productivity, creativity, and job satisfaction
- Conducting a research project on the relatiship between HR policies and innovation at Japanese enterprises

Collaborative Researcher

• German Institute for Japanese Studies (DIJ)

- Quantitative data analysis for the project related to Japan's economic and demographic tendencies
- Collaborative work on spatial data analysis, text mining and survey data analysis

Part-Time Researcher & Admin Assistant

Business Sciences, Humanities and Social Sciences

University of Tsukuba

- Conducting a research project "Market Perception of Corporate Innovations in Japan"
- Supporting the Special Program in Japanese and Eurasian Studies (SPJES)

2019 • **Postdoc**

2018

2018

2015

2020

Business Sciences, Humanities and Social Sciences

University of Tsukuba

- Working on the project "Japanese Employment Practices and Innovation Strategies"
- Providing academic support to the Master- and PhD-students at the International and Advanced Japanese Studies department

Teaching Assistant

Business Sciences, Humanities and Social Sciences

◆ University of Tsukuba

- International Political Economy II: The Politics of Development (1 April 2016 – 30 June 2016; 1 April 2017 – 30 June 2017; 1 April 2018 – 30 June 2018)
- · Comparative Politics III: Public Policy and Management (1 October 2016 28 February 2017; 1 October 2017 28 February 2018)
- · Introduction to Southeast Asian Studies (1 October 2015 20 December 2015)

2013

Intern

Outreach Unit

- **Q** UN Information Service (UNIS), Vienna, Austria
- \cdot Wrote reports for the UNIS website and for the UN intranet platform
- Provided logistic support to UNIS consultants in the client countries (Hungary, Slovakia, Slovenia)
- \cdot Helped with production of new teaching materials on Millennium Development Goals (MDGs) and post-2015 agenda



PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

2018

Impact of Shareholder-Value Pursuit on Labor Policies at Japanese Joint-Stock Companies: Case of Nikkei Index 400

The Japanese Political Economy. 35(2), 1-32

· Taylor & Francis Online

2017

Corporate Governance Reforms in Japan: Instilling the New Regime Cogent Business & Management. 4(1), 1-16

· Taylor & Francis Online



MANUSCRIPTS UNDER REVIEW AND IN PROGRESS

2021

Does Tokyo Stock Exchange Appreciate Corporate Innovations? Role of Patents' Quality and Research Productivity

Preprint available as SocArXiv publication. https://doi.org/10.31235/osf .io/k4ys6

· Under review

2021

Sustainable Communities: Determinants of Municipal Fiscal Health in

(co-authored with Franz Waldenberger)

· Work in progress

SELECTED CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

2019

The Role of Labor Flexibility in the Pursuit of Innovation Strategies by **Established Japanese Companies**

Society for the Advancement of Socio-Economics (SASE) 31st Annual Meeting

· New School, New York, U.S.

2017

Impact of Shareholder-Value Pursuit on Labor Policies at Japanese Joint-Stock Companies: Case of Nikkei Index 400

Academy of International Business (AIB) Annual Conference

· Dubai, U.A.E.

Impact of Financialization on Labor Policies at Japanese Joint-Stock Companies: Case of Nikkei Index 400

World Interdisciplinary Network for Institutional Research (WINIR) Conference

· Boston, U.S.

Institutional Context of the Recent Corporate Governance Reforms in Japan

Australia and New Zealand International Business Academy (ANZIBA) Conference

· University of Sydney, Sydney, AU

& AWARDS & GRANTS

Japan Society for the Promotion of Science
Grant-in-Aid for Young Scientists (B)

• The Role of Labor Flexibility in the Pursuit of Innovation Strategies

2021 • European Commission

Seal of Excellence

♥ H2020-MSCA-IF-2020

• The Role of Employment Policies and Corporate Governance in the Pursuit of Innovation Strategies: Comparative Analysis of France, Germany and Japan

2018 • Foundation France-Japon/SASE

Best Paper Award

Obshisha University, Kyoto

• Impact of Shareholder-Value Pursuit on Labor Policies at Japanese Joint-Stock Companies: Case of Nikkei Index 400

Society for the Advancement of Socio-Economics (SASE)

Early Career Workshop Award

• Impact of Shareholder-Value Pursuit on Labor Policies at Japanese Joint-Stock Companies: Case of Nikkei Index 400

THE ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Current | 2018

2018

2019

Society Member

- · Society for the Advancement of Socio-Economics (SASE)
- · European Association for Japanese Studies (EAJS)

Current | 2017

Paper Reviewer

- · Asian Business and Management (Palgrave Macmillan)
- · Economics of Innovation and New Technology (Taylor & Francis Online)
- · Cogent Business & Management (Taylor & Francis Online)

